#### CONTACT



## **ANUBHAVA RANJAN**

anubhava.ranjan03@gmail.com



7042292056

New Delhi



# **OBJECTIVE**

To join an organization that will recognise and utilise my skills in a effective way and offer me a position requiring innovative and creative notions where continuous growth and learning are ways of life.

## **CAREER SUMMARY**

Having total of **4 years** of professional experience in **Java** for developing projects in support of application software for the Manufacturing process.

Presently designated as **Senior Programmaer** in **Silver Touch Technologies Ltd**. at client side **(National Informatics Center)**.

**4 years** of experience in Java as Core Java, Collections, Servlet, JSP, Spring 4.0, SpringBoot2.0, OAuth2.0, JWT, Microservices, Hibernate, Struts 2.0, Web Services Restful by (JSON).

Good Experience in Postgres and Oracle Database.

IDE used Eclipse and Jdeveloper 12c.

Webserver Apache Tomcat.

## **EXPERIENCE**

April 2018 - Till now

Silver Touch Technologies Ltd.

Senior Programmer

Designated as Senior Programmaer and get exposure to develop various applications for client side (National Informatics Center). Currently working projects like Intellectual Property Rights and ICT.

Dec 2014 - Feb 2018

Kenmax Business Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

Software Engineer

From Dec 2014 to July 2016 designated as a Tester. Through IJP (Internal Job Paper) promoted as Software Engineer. From August 2016 to February 2018 designated as a developer and get exposure to develop an application in Java.

### **PROJECTS**

### Intellectual Property Rights (IPR)

Client :- National Informatics Center

**Description:- IPR** is a software belongs to the **custom** department of **Indian Government,** which deals with property rights. The first part of the application where user registers Trademark Registration, Copyright Registration, Design Registation and Geographical Indication Registration. The second part of this software deals with the internal departmental work allocation of officers and the officers respond towards the registration through this application.

**Technologies used:-** Spring 4.0, Hibernate 3.0, Core Java, JSP, HTML, CSS, Java Script, Ajax, Restful web Services (JSON), Oracle, Apache Tomcat.

**ICT** 

Client:- National Informatics Center

**Description:- ICT** is a software deals with the data of e-procurement of items required by government organizations. The software used by the internal committee of ICT officers. It simplifies the movement of the records. After approval of committee the user can easily procure their requirements through biding.

**Technologies used:**- SpringBoot 2.0, Hibernate 5.2, JSP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Ajax , jQuery, Postgres. Tomcat.

## **Cash Management System**

**CMS** is a software that efficiently manage cash flow in order to reduce risks, minimize expenses and maximize profits. The project manages all the expenses like electric bill, phone bill, water tender etc. There is a tender module for the submission of the tender for the different branch of the business.

**Technology used**:- Struts2.0, JDBC, CoreJava, JSP, Servlet, Java Script, AJAX, Postgres

## **SKILLS**

Spring 4.0

Spring Boot 2.0

OAuth2.0

JWT

Microservices

Web Services Restful (JSON)

Hibernate

Core Java

**JSP** 

Servlet

Oracle

Postgres

**Eclipse** 

Jdeveloper 12c

### **EDUCATION**

2010-2014

### THE ICFAI University, Dehradun

B.Tech (Computer Science)

7.64 CGPA

2010

### M.S College

**Higher Senior Secondary** 

69%

2008

## Zila School

Senior Secondary (10th)

73%